Life doesn't hold tryouts.
Center Stage is a drama, music film directed by Nicholas Hytner.
A group of 12 teenagers from various backgrounds enroll at the American Ballet Academy in New York to make it as ballet
dancers and each one deals with the problems and stress of training and getting ahead in the world of dance.
Jody Sawyer, played by Amanda Schull.
Eva Rodríguez, played by Zoe Saldaña.
Jonathan Reeves, played by Peter Gallagher.
Cooper, played by Ethan Stiefel.
Juliette, played by Donna Murphy.
Maureen Cummings, played by Susan May Pratt.
Center Stage is a 2000 American teen drama film directed by Nicholas Hytner about a group of young ballet dancers
from various backgrounds who enroll at the fictitious American Ballet Academy in New York City.
The film explores the issues and difficulties in the world of professional
dance, and how each individual copes with the stresses.
It also served as the film debut for actresses Zoe Saldaña and Amanda Schull.
The film was released theatrically in the United States on May 12, 2000.
The single from the film's soundtrack "I Wanna Be
with You" is performed by Mandy Moore.
The song became Moore's highest-charting song in the US at number
24, becoming her only top 40 song in the nation.
It spent 16 weeks on the Billboard Hot 100, and
peaked during its 9th week on the chart.
The film explores themes of career, new york city, dance, dancer, competition.
The tone is emotional.